# **CHAD HOROHOE**

# Senior Site Reliability Engineer // DevOps Practitioner

#### **Phone**

+14159373151

#### **Email**

chad@horohoe.email

#### LinkedIn

https://linkedin.com/in/chad-horohoe

#### **Skills**

Kubernetes, AWS, Debian/ Ubuntu, Docker, Terraform, Python, Git/ GitHub, Redis, MongoDB, Elasticsearch, Mysql, Java, Prometheus, Grafana

#### **Profile**

Building tools for small teams of engineers in a single location. Serving knowledge to hundreds of millions of users across the globe. Helped to put vaccines in the arms of hundreds of thousands of patients during a global pandemic. For well over a decade, I've helped organizations scale using the best tools at hand. Always curious, I'm always striving to learn more and excel in my line of work.

## Experience

Senior Site Reliability Engineer, Luma Health :: January 2020-April 2021

Migrated company infrastructure from third-party container hosting to in-house managed Kubernetes installation on AWS, at a cost savings of roughly 70% per month. Also built out entirely new GitOps-driven CI/CD pipeline backed by Flux to accelerate deployments of new code. Drove adoption of numerous improvements to company security stance, including: a password manager, SSO for most internal applications, and hardware security keys for admin users.

Senior Software Engineer, ASAPP Inc :: June 2018 – December 2019

Migrated company from github.com to self-hosted Github Enterprise. Implemented company-wide tagging policies for AWS resources for compliance and cost optimization. Provided ongoing infrastructure & architectural consultation for other teams. Transitioned 200+ engineers from individual IAM Users to shared IAM Roles per team. Provisioned all new and documented existing infrastructure as code via Terraform.

Senior Software Engineer, Wikimedia Foundation :: January 2016—June 2018 Redesigned CI/CD pipeline, which orchestrated efficient large-scale production software deployments. Production support, including debugging and troubleshooting post-deployment issues.

Software Engineer, Wikimedia Foundation:: June 2010—January 2016
Researched, designed and implemented scalable replacement for aging in-house full-text search engine. Reviewed PHP code across multiple subsystems, providing actionable feedback and learning opportunities for fellow engineers.

### Education

Virginia Commonwealth University — B.S. in Information Systems, 2012